James McKeen Cattell Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Part II: General Correspondence, 1880-1940 (Box 96-160)
  - Keen, William W.
  - Keller, Albert G.
  - Kelley, Eugene R.
  - Kellogg, Vernon L.
  - Kelly, Howard A.
  - Kelsey, Francis W.
  - Kemmerer, Edwin W.
  - Kemp, George T.
  - Kemp, James F.
  - Kendall, Arthur I.
  - Kendall, Calvin N.
  - Kennelly, Arthur E.
  - Keppel, Frederick P.
  - Kettering, Charles F.
  - Keys, Ancel
  - Keyser, Cassius J.
  - Kilpatrick, William H.
  - Kingsley, Clarence D.
  - Kingsley, John S.
  - Kinley, David (Box 127)
  - Kinnicutt, Leonard P.
  - Kirchwey, George W.
  - Klonower, Henry
  - Klotz, Otto J.
  - Knopf, S. Adolphus
  - Knower, Henry M.
  - Knowles, James Thomas
  - Knowlton, Frank H.
  - Kofoid, Charles A.
  - Kohler, Wolfgang
  - Kolbe, Parke R.
  - Koo, Vi Kyuin
  - Korstian, C. F.
  - Korzybski, Alfred
  - Kraatz, Walter C.
  - Kraus, Charles A.
  - Kraus, Edward H.
  - Kremers, Edward
  - Kroeber, Alfred L.
  - Kunz, George F.
  - “Ka-Kin” miscellaneous
  - “Kip-Ky” miscellaneous (Box 128)
  - Ladd, George Trumbull
  - Ladd, William S.
  - LaGorce, John C.
  - Laidler, Harry W.
  - Laird, Donald A.
  - Lamb, Arthur B.
  - Lamson-Scribner, Frank
  - Lancaster, H. Carrington
  - Landauer, Walter
  - Landsteiner, Karl
  - Lange, Alexis F.
  - Lange, Ludwig
  - Langenbeck, Karl
  - Langfeld, Herbert S.
  - Langley, Samuel P.
  - Langmuir, Irving (Box 129)
  - Lanman, Charles R.
  - Lansing, Robert
  - Lape, Esther E.
  - Larned, Josephus N.
  - Lashley, Karl S.
  - Latourette, Kenneth S.
  - Laufer, Berthold
  - Laurence, William L.
  - Lazier, Edgar L.
  - Lecomte du Nouy, Pierre
  - Lee, Frederic E.
  - Lehmer, Derrick N.
  - Leidy, Joseph
  - Leiper, Joseph M.
  - Leith, Charles K.
  - Leitzell, Ted
  - Leland, Waldo G.
  - LeRossignol, James E.
  - Leuschner, Armin O.
  - Levene, Phoebus A.
  - Leverett, Frank
  - Lewis, Frederic T.
  - Lewis, Gilbert N.
  - Lewis, Robert, Jr.
  - Lewis, William M.
  - Lewisohn, Adolph
  - Libby, Frederick J.
  - Library of Congress
  - Lieb, John W.
  - Lillie, Frank R.
  - Lillie, Ralph S.
  - Lind, Samuel C.
  - Lindbergh, Charles A.
  - Lindenthal, Gustav
  - Lindgren, Waldemar
  - Lindley, Ernest H.
  - Lindquist, Rudolph D. (Box 130)
  - Lindsay, Samuel McCune
  - Link, Henry C.
  - Lipman, Jacob G.
  - Little, Arthur D.
  - Little, Clarence C.
  - Livingston, Arthur
  - Livingston, Burton E.
  - Lloyd, Alfred H.
  - Lloyd, Morton G.
  - Lodge, Gonzalez
  - Lodge, Oliver
  - Loeb, Jacques
  - Loeb, Leo
  - Loeb, Leonard B.
  - Lomb, Adolph
  - Lombard, Warren P.
  - Long, Esmond R.
  - Long, John H.
  - Loosanoff, Victor L.
  - Lory, Charles A.
  - Lovejoy, Arthur O. (Box 131)
  - Lovett, Edgar O.
  - Lovett, Robert M.
  - Low, Seth
  - Lowell, A. Lawrence
  - Lowell, Percival
  - Lowie, Robert H.
  - Lucas, Frederic A.
  - Luckiesh, Matthew
  - Lufts, J. H.
  - Lull, Richard S.
  - Lundberg, Ferdinand
  - Lusk, Graham
  - Lutz, Frank E.
  - Lyman, Theodore
  - Lyon, Elias P.
  - “Lac-Leh” miscellaneous
  - “Lei-Ly” miscellaneous (Box 132)
  - McAdie, Alexander (Box 133)
  - McAndrew, William
  - McCann, William S.
  - McChesney, Evan W.
  - McClung, Clarence E.
  - McClure, Harriet H.
  - McCollum, Elmer V.
  - McCormick, Samuel B.
  - McConaughy, James L.
  - McCracken, Charles C.
  - MacCracken, John H.
  - MacCurdy, George Grant
  - MacCurdy, Hansford M.
  - MacDonald, Arthur
  - MacDougal, Daniel T.
  - MacDougall, Robert
  - McEwen, Alexander F.
  - McGee, William J.
  - McGiffert, Arthur G.
  - MacGillivray, Alexander D.
  - McGrath, John J.
  - MacKenzie, James C.
  - McKenzie, Robert Tait
  - McKinley, Earl B.
  - McKinney, Thomas E.
  - McLaughlin, Andrew C.
  - MacLaurin, Richard C.
  - McLean, Donald A.
  - MacLean, George E.
  - McLennan, John C.
  - Macleod, John J. R. (Box 134)
  - McMurrich, James P.
  - McMurray, Frank M.
  - McPherson, William
  - McVey, Frank L.
  - “Mc” miscellaneous
  - Mackie, Maria (Box 135)
  - Maddox, John J.
  - Magie, William F.
  - Manahan, James
  - Manning, William T.
  - Mark, Edward L.
  - Marsh, Othniel C.
  - Marshall, Francis H. A.
  - Marshall, Henry R.
  - Marshall, James
  - Martin, Lawrence
  - Marvin, Charles F.
  - Marvin, Cloyd H.
  - Mason, Otis T.
  - Massey, Vincent
  - Mather, Kirtley F.
  - Mathews, Albert P.
  - Mathews, Joseph H.
  - Matthew, William D.
  - Maxim, Hudson
  - Maxwell, Perriton
  - Mayer, Alfred G.
  - Mead, George H.
  - Means, Philip A.
  - Mees, Charles E. K.
  - Meiklejoh, Alexander
  - Melander, Axel L.
  - Meltzer, Samuel J.
  - Melville, George W.
  - Mendel, Lafayette B.
  - Mendenhall, Thomas C.
  - Mendenhall, Walter C.
  - Menninger, Karl A.
  - Mercer, Samuel A. B.
  - Merriam, C. Hart
  - Merriam, John C.
  - Merrill, Elmer D.
  - Merrill, George P.
  - Merriman, Mansfield
  - Merz, Charles
  - Meyer, Adolf
  - Meyer, Arthur W.
  - Mezes, Sidney
  - Michelson, Albert A.
  - Milam, Carl H.
  - Miles, Walter R.
  - Miller, Charles R.
  - Miller, Dayton C.
  - Miller, Dickinson S.
  - Miller, George A.
  - Miller, H. S.
  - Miller, Kelly (Box 136)
  - Miller, Newman
  - Miller, W. Lash
  - Millikan, Robert A.
  - Mills, Ogden L.
  - Minnich, Dwight E.
  - Minot, Charles S.
  - Minot, George R.
  - Mitchel, John Purroy
  - Mitchell, Guy E.
  - Mitchell, Samuel A.
  - Mitchell, Wesley C.
  - Moe, Henry Allen
  - Mohler, John R.
  - Monroe, Paul
  - Montague, William P.
  - Mooney, James
  - Moore, Barrington
  - Moore, Charles
  - Moore, Elizkim H.
  - Moore, George T.
  - Moore, John Bassett
  - Moore, Richard B.
  - Moore, Veranus Alva
  - Moorehead, Warren K.
  - More, Louis T.
  - Morehouse, Daniel W.
  - Morgan, Arthur E.
  - Morgan, John L. R.
  - Morgan, Joy E.
  - Morgan, Thomas H.
  - Morris, Robert T.
  - Morris, Roland S.
  - Morse, Edward S.
  - Morse, Harmon N.
  - Mortenson, Peter A.
  - Moulton, Elton J.
  - Moulton, Forest R.
  - Muirhead, James F.
  - Muller, Hermann J.
  - Mumford, Lewis
  - Munroe, Charles E.
  - Munsterberg, Hugo
  - Murlin, Lemuel
  - Murphree, Albert A.
  - Murphy, Robert C.
  - Mussey, Henry R.
  - “Mab-Met” miscellaneous (Box 137)
  - “Mey-Mor” miscellaneous (Box 138)
  - “Mos-My” miscellaneous (Box 139)
  - Nagel, Charles
  - National Academy of Sciences
  - National Education Association
  - Nearing, Scott
  - Needham, J. Garton
  - Nef, John U.
  - Nelson, Edward W.
  - New, Harry S.
  - New Era Printing Co.
  - Newbold, William R.
  - Newcomb, Simon
  - Newell, Frederick H.
  - Newman, Horatio H.
  - Nichols, Edward L.
  - Nichols, Ernest F. (Box 140)
  - Nichols, William H.
  - Nipher, Francis E.
  - Nixon, H. Clarence
  - Nock, Alfred Jay
  - Norlin, George
  - Northrop, John H.
  - Norton, Charles D.
  - Norton, Thomas H.
  - Novy, Frederick G.
  - Noyes, Alexander D.
  - Noyes, Arthur A.
  - Noyes, Harry A.
  - Noyes, William A.
  - Nuttall, Zelia
  - Nutting, Charles C.
  - “Na-Ni” miscellaneous
  - “No-Ny” miscellaneous (Box 141)
  - Oberholser, Harry C.
  - Odum, Howard W.
  - Ogden, Rollo
  - Olds, George D.
  - Olmsted Brothers
  - Olson, Oliver
  - O'Malley, Henry
  - Opie, Eugene L.
  - Ortmann, Arnold E.
  - Orton, Edward, Jr.
  - Osborn, Henry Fairfield
  - Osborn, Herbert
  - Osborne, Thomas B.
  - Osgood, William F.
  - Osler, William
  - Osterhout, Winthrop J. V.
  - Owen, Robert L.
  - Owens, Robert Bowie
  - “O” miscellaneous (Box 142)
  - Pace, Edward A.
  - Page, Leigh
  - Page, Walter Hines
  - Palmer, Archie M.
  - Palmer, George H.
  - Palmer, Theodore S.
  - Papanicolaou, George N.
  - Parker, George H.
  - Parsons, Charles L.
  - Parsons, Claude V.
  - Parsons, Edward S.
  - Parsons, William B.
  - Pasvolsky, Leo
  - Paterson, Donald G.
  - Patten, Simon N.
  - Patterson, Austin M.
  - Patrick, Walter A.
  - Pavlov, Ivan P.
  - Payne, Kenneth W.
  - Peabody, George Foster
  - Pearl, Raymond
  - Pearl, Raymond (Box 143)
  - Pearson, Karl
  - Pearson, Raymond A.
  - Peck, Harry T.
  - Pegram, George B.
  - Peirce, Charles S.
  - Peirce, George J.
  - Peirce, Harold
  - Penck, Albrecht
  - Pender, Harold
  - Pendleton, Ellen F.
  - Penniman, Josiah H.
  - Perret, Frank A.
  - Perrine, Charles D.
  - Perry, Edward D.
  - Perry, Ralph Barton
  - Petrunkevitch, Alexander
  - Petrunkevitch, Wanda
  - Phelps, William Lyon
  - Phillips, John S.
  - Phillips, William
  - Pickering, Edward C.
  - Pierce, Roger
  - Pieters, Adrian J.
  - Pillsbury, Walter B.
  - Pinchot, Amos
  - Pinchot, Gifford
  - Pincus, Gregory
  - Pintner, Rudolf
  - Pirsson, Louis V.
  - Pitkin, Walter B.
  - Poffenberger, Albert T.
  - Poor, Charles Lane
  - Popence, Paul B.
  - Porter, Jermain G.
  - Poteat, William L.
  - Poulton, Edward B.
  - Pound, Roscoe
  - Power, Frederick B.
  - Prince, John D.
  - Prince, Morton
  - Pritchett, Henry S.
  - Prudden, T. Mitchell
  - Pumpelly, Raphael
  - Pupin, Michael T.
  - Putnam, Frederic W.
  - Putnam, George H.
  - “Pac-Ph” miscellaneous (Box 144)
  - “Pi-Py” miscellaneous (Box 145)
  - “Q” miscellaneous
  - Radin, Paul
  - Ransome, Frederick L.
  - Rao, C. R. Narayan
  - Rayleigh, Lord
  - Reader's Digest
  - Redfield, Henry S.
  - Reichert, Edward T.
  - Reid, Harry Fielding
  - Remsen, Ira
  - Rhine, Joseph B.
  - Rhodes, James F.
  - Richards, Charles R.
  - Richards, Ellen H.
  - Richards, Theodore W.
  - Richardson, Owen W.
  - Richtmyer, Floyd K.
  - Riddle, Oscar
  - Ridgway, Robert
  - Ridsdale, Percival S.
  - Rieber, Charles H.
  - Riesman, David
  - Rivers, William H. R.
  - Roberts, Arthur J.
  - Roberts, Frank H. H., Jr.
  - Robertson, David
  - Robertson, George C.
  - Robinson, Benjamin L.
  - Robinson, Frederick B.
  - Robinson, James H.
  - Rockefeller, John D., Jr.
  - Rodale, Jerome I.
  - Roe, Gilbert E.
  - Rogers, James F.
  - Rogers, Samuel L.
  - Rogers, Will
  - Rolfe, Henry W.
  - Roos, Charles F. (Box 146)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D.
  - Roosevelt, George Emlen
  - Roosevelt, Theodore
  - Rosa, Edward B.
  - Rose, Joseph N.
  - Rosenau, Milton J.
  - Ross, Edward A.
  - Ross, Ronald
  - Rostovtzeff, Michael I.
  - Rotch, Abbott L.
  - Rous, Peyton
  - Royce, Josiah
  - Royce, Katharine
  - Rubinow, Sidney G.
  - Ruedemann, Rudolf
  - Ruedemann, Walter A.
  - Ruffin, James E.
  - Rugg, Harold C.
  - Ruml, Beardsley
  - Rusby, Henry H.
  - Rushmore, Stephen
  - Russell, Henry N.
  - Russell, James E.
  - Russell, Walter
  - Russell, William F.
  - Ruthven, Alexandria G.
  - Ryan, W. Carson, Jr.
  - “Rab-Red” miscellaneous
  - “Ree-Ross” miscellaneous (Box 147)
  - “Rot-Ry” miscellaneous (Box 148)
  - Sabin, Albert B.
  - Sabin, Florence R.
  - Sabine, Wallace C. W.
  - Sadtler, Samuel P.
  - Safford, Truman H.
  - Sage, John H.
  - Salisbury, Rollin D.
  - Salmon, Thomas W.
  - Sanford, Edmund C.
  - Sapir, Edward
  - Sargent, Dudley A.
  - Sargent, Epes
  - Sarton, George A. L.
  - Saunders, Frederick A.
  - Sayles, Robert W.
  - Schaeberle, John M.
  - Schaeffer, Asa A.
  - Schaeffer, John A.
  - Schell, Erwin H.
  - Schelling, Felix E.
  - Schlesinger, Frank
  - Schuchert, Charles
  - Schurman, Jacob G.
  - Schuster, M. Lincoln
  - Schwab, John C.
  - Scott, Hugh
  - Scott, Walter D.
  - Scott, William A.
  - Scott, William B.
  - Scripture, Edward W.
  - Scudder, Samuel H.
  - Seares, Frederick H.
  - Sears, Paul B.
  - Seashore, Carl E.
  - Sedgwich, William T.
  - See, Thomas J. J.
  - Seligman, Edwin R. A.
  - Serviss, Garrett P. (Box 149)
  - Seth, James
  - Sewell, John S.
  - Shaffer, Philip A.
  - Shaler, Nathaniel S.
  - Shantz, Homer L.
  - Shapley, Harlow
  - Shaw, Wilfred B.
  - Shawkey, Morris P.
  - Shear, Cornelius L.
  - Shelford, Victor E.
  - Sherman, Henry C.
  - Sherwood, George H.
  - Shimer, Porter W.
  - Shipley, Arthur E.
  - Shufeldt, Robert W.
  - Shull, Aaron F.
  - Shull, Charles A.
  - Shull, George H.
  - Simmons, George H.
  - Simpson, George G.
  - Simpson, Howard E.
  - Sinclair, Upton
  - Singer, Isidor
  - Singh, B. N.
  - Sisson, Edward C.
  - Skillman, David B.
  - Slade, Albert A.
  - Slipher, Vesto M.
  - Sloan, Alfred P., Jr.
  - Slosson, Edwin E.
  - Small, John K.
  - Smith, Alexander
  - Smith, Alfred E.
  - Smith, Benjamin E.
  - Smith, David E.
  - Smith, Edgar F.
  - Smith, Erwin F.
  - Smith, George C.
  - Smith, Grafton E.
  - Smith, Harrison W.
  - Smith, Hugh McC.
  - Smith, J. Allen
  - Smith, Lewis W.
  - Smith, Munroe
  - Smith, Payson
  - Smith, Percy F.
  - Smith, Theobald
  - Smith, William W.
  - Snedden, David
  - Soddy, Frederick
  - Soule, Malcolm H.
  - Southall, James P. C.
  - Southard, Elmer E.
  - Spaulding, Edward G.
  - Spencer, William H.
  - Speyer, James
  - Spillman, William J.
  - Spingarn, Joel E.
  - Spinning, James M.
  - Springer, Frank
  - Spurr, Josiah (Box 150)
  - Stanley, Wendell M.
  - Starbuck, Edwin D.
  - Starr, M. Allen
  - Stebbing, Thomas R. R.
  - Stebbins, Joel
  - Steenbock, Harry
  - Stefansson, Vilhjalmur
  - Stephens, Henry M.
  - Stevens, James S.
  - Stevenson, Burton
  - Stevenson, Edward L.
  - Stewart, George N.
  - Stewart, Russell C.
  - Stieglitz, Julius
  - Stiles, Charles W.
  - Stockard, Charles R.
  - Stoddard, Francis H.
  - Stokes, Anson Phelps
  - Stokes, Edward L.
  - Stokes, William E. Dodge
  - Stokley, James S.
  - Stone, Harlan F.
  - Stone, Witmer
  - Stoner, Dayton
  - Stopes, Marie
  - Storer, Horatio R.
  - Storey, Thomas A.
  - Stoughton, Bradley
  - Stout, George F.
  - Stratton, George M.
  - Stratton, Samuel W.
  - Straus, Oscar S.
  - Strong, Charles A.
  - Strong, Frank
  - Strong, Richard P.
  - Studebaker, John W.
  - Sturdivant, Jessie L.
  - Sullivan, Mark
  - Suzzallo, Henry
  - Sverdrup, Harold U.
  - Swain, Joseph
  - Swann, William F. G.
  - Swasey, Ambrose
  - Swift, Otis Peabody
  - Swingle, Walter T.
  - Sykes, Frederick H.
  - Symonds, John Addington
  - Symonds, Percival M.
  - Szold, Henrietta
  - “Sab-Say” miscellaneous
  - “Sca-Smith, F." miscellaneous (Box 151)
  - “Smith, G.-Sto” miscellaneous (Box 152)
  - “Str-Sy” miscellaneous (Box 153)
  - Takamine, Jokichi, Jr.
  - Tarr, Ralph S.
  - Tatlock, John S. P.
  - Taussig, Frank W.
  - Taylor, Henry Osborn
  - Taylor, Norman
  - TenBroeck, Carl
  - Terman, Lewis M.
  - Teubner, Benediktus G.
  - Thatcher, Roscoe W.
  - Thaxter, Roland
  - Thayer, Abbott H.
  - Thayer, William S.
  - Thilly, Frank
  - Thomas, Calvin
  - Thomas, John M.
  - Thomas, Martha Carey
  - Thompson, Joseph O.
  - Thompson, William O.
  - Thomson, Elihu
  - Thomson, Francis A.
  - Thomson, Godfrey H.
  - Thomson, John Arthur
  - Thorndike, Ashley H.
  - Thorndike, Edward L.
  - Thorndike, Lynn
  - Thwing, Charles F.
  - Tigert, John James
  - Tinney, Albert
  - Titchener, Edward B.
  - Toch, Maximilian
  - Todd, Thomas W.
  - Tolman, Richard C.
  - Toumey, James W.
  - Townsend, Charles H.
  - Trask, James D.
  - Trelease, Sam F.
  - Trelease, William
  - Troland, Leonard T.
  - Trowbridge, Augustus
  - Trudeau, Edward L.
  - True, Alfred C.
  - True, Rodney H.
  - Tufts, James H.
  - Tulloss, Rees E.
  - Tumulty, Joseph
  - Turner, Edward R. (Box 154)
  - Turner, Herbert H.
  - Turner, Thomas W.
  - Twenhofel, William H.
  - Tyler, Harry W.
  - “T” miscellaneous (Box 155)
  - Uchida, Yasuya
  - Ufer, Walter
  - Uhrbrock, Richard S.
  - Untermyer, Samuel
  - Upham, Warren
  - Urban, Wilbur M.
  - Urey, Harold C.
  - “U” miscellaneous
  - Van Amringe, John H.
  - Van Doren, Carl
  - Van Hise, Charles R.
  - Van Name, Willard G.
  - Van Slyke, Donald D.
  - Van Slyke, Lucius L.
  - Vaughan, Victor C.
  - Veblen, Oswald
  - Venable, Francis P.
  - Verrill, Addison E.
  - Very, Frank W.
  - Villard, Oswald G.
  - Vincent, George E.
  - Virkus, Frederick A.
  - Volwiler, Ernest H.
  - “V” miscellaneous
  - Wadsworth, James W., Jr. (Box 156)
  - Wait, Lucien A.
  - Waksman, Selman A.
  - Walcott, Charles D.
  - Walcott, Frederick C.
  - Walker, William H.
  - Wallace, Henry Agard
  - Wallace, Robert C.
  - Walters, Raymond
  - Walz, William E.
  - Ward, Henry B.
  - Ward, James
  - Ward, Lester F.
  - Ward, Robert DeC.
  - Ware, William R.
  - Warfield, Ethelbert D.
  - Warner, Worcester R. (Box 157)
  - Warren, George F.
  - Warren, Howard C.
  - Warren, John C.
  - Warthin, Aldred S.
  - Washington, Henry S.
  - Wateneys, Hardolph
  - Watson, John B.
  - Watson, Mark S.
  - Waugh, Frank A.
  - Webber, Herbert J.
  - Wechsler, James
  - Weidlein, Edward R.
  - Welch, William H.
  - Welles, Sumner
  - Wells, Frederic Lyman
  - Wenley, Robert M.
  - Wertham, Frederic
  - Wesbrook, Frank F.
  - West, Andrew F.
  - West, Olin
  - Westerdijk, Johan
  - Wetmore, Alexander
  - Whalen, Grover
  - Wheeler, Wayne B.
  - Wheeler, Wayne B.
  - Wheeler, William M.
  - Whipple, George C.
  - Whipple, Guy M.
  - Whitbeck, Ray Hughes
  - White, Israel C.
  - White, William Alanson
  - Whitehead, John B.
  - Whiting, Phineas W.
  - Whitlock, Herbert P.
  - Whitman, Charles O.
  - Whitney, Willis R.
  - Wigmore, John H.
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman
  - Wilder, Burt G.
  - Wilder, Harris H.
  - Wiley, Harvey W.
  - Wilkins, Ernest H.
  - Willcox, Walter F.
  - Willcox, William G.
  - Williams, Edward H.
  - Williams, J. Whitridge
  - Williams, John W.
  - Willis, Bailey
  - Williston, Samuel W.
  - Wilson, Edmund Beecher
  - Wilson, Edwin B.
  - Wilson, Edwin B. (Box 158)
  - Wilson, Guy M.
  - Wilson, Herbert C.
  - Wilson, Louis B.
  - Wilson, Louis R.
  - Wilson, Milburn L.
  - Wilson, Woodrow
  - Winchell, Newton H.
  - Wise, Stephen S.
  - Wissler, Clark
  - Witschi, Emil
  - Wolfe, Albert B.
  - Wood, Ben D.
  - Wood, Horatio C.
  - Wood, Lee B.
  - Wood, Robert W.
  - Woodbridge, Frederick J. E.
  - Woodhouse, Henry
  - Woods, Albert F.
  - Woods, Arthur
  - Woods, Frederick A.
  - Woods, William
  - Woodward, Arthur Smith
  - Woodward, Calvin M.
  - Woodward, Robert S.
  - Woodworth, Robert S.
  - Wooley, Mary E.
  - Wright, Arthur W.
  - Wright, George Frederick
  - Wright, Jonathan
  - Wright, Sewall
  - Wroth, Lawrence C.
  - Wundt, Wilhelm
  - “Wac-War” miscellaneous
  - “Was-Will” miscellaneous (Box 159)
  - “Wila-Wy” miscellaneous (Box 160)
  - Yerkes, Robert M.
  - Yoakum, Clarence S.
  - Young, Allyne A.
  - Young, Charles A.
  - Young, Ella Flagg
  - Young, Hugh H.
  - “Y” miscellaneous
  - Zinkelsen, Max
  - Zinsser, Hans
  - Zook, George F.
  - “Z” miscellaneous
  - Unidentified
  - Stenographic notebook of correspondence with various persons
- Part II: Subject File, 1890-1936 (Box 161-185)
  Correspondence and related papers.
  Grouped by subject and arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, (14 folders); (17 folders); (12 folders); (11 folders); (8 folders) (Box 161, Box 162, Box 163, Box 164, Box 165, Box 166, Box 167, Box 168)
  - American Association of University Professors
  - American Psychological Association
  - Biographical Directory of American Men of Science, (9 folders); (7 folders); (8 folders) (Box 169, Box 170, Box 171)
  - Biographical Directory of Leaders in Education
  - Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching
  - Century Club
  - Code of Fair Competition
  - Columbia University, New York, N.Y., (1 folder); (10 folders); (7 folders); (8 folders) (Box 172, Box 173, Box 174, Box 175, Box 176)
  - Doctors of philosophy, lists, (4 folders); (1 folder) (Box 177)
  - Eugenics, International Commission on
  - Hillquit, Morris
  - National Academy of Sciences
  - Popular Science Monthly
  - Progressive Science Series, (2 folders); (8 folders) (Box 178)
  - Psychological Corp.
  - Psychological Review
  - Psychologists in foreign countries, survey, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box 179)
  - Psychology
    - Examination papers, laboratory tests, lecture notes
    - Lecture notes, (6 folders); (13 folders); (4 folders) (Box 180, Box 181)
    - Ninth International Congress of Psychology
  - School and Society, (9 folders)
  - Science, (1 folder); (11 folders); (8 folders) (Box 182, Box 183)
  - Science Press Printing Co., (7 folders) (Box 184)
  - Science Service, (2 folders)
  - Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C., secretaryship (1906), (2 folders); (5 folders) (Box 185)
- Part II: Speech, Article, and Book File, 1875-1935 (Box 185-187)
  Literary manuscripts.
  Grouped by type of material and therein alphabetically.
  - Speeches (Box 185)
    - "Psychology in War and Education, Comparative Methods"
    - Fragments
  - Articles
    - "Suggestions for the Announcement of the American Institute of Psychology
    - "American Society of Naturalists"
    - "An Apology for my Life at Columbia"
    - "Causes of the Declining Birth Rate"
    - "Classification of Duties and Virtues"
    - "Concerning Advertising in Scientific Periodicals"
    - "Controlled Press"
    - "Corporation for the Advancement of Psychology"
    - "Declining Family and Its Causes"
    - "Diminishing Family"
    - "Distribution of American Men of Science in 1927"
    - "Early Psychological Laboratories"
    - "Encyclopedia of the Sciences"
    - "Esoteric Psychology"
    - "Examinations, Grades, and Credits"
    - "Experiments on the Assoc. of Ideas"
    - "Families of American Men of Science"
    - "Freshmen Tests"
    - "How to Understand the Montessori Method"
    - "In Defense of Academic Freedom" (Box 186)
    - "Journal 'Science' and the American Assoc. for the Advancement of Science"
    - "Letters to the Trustees of Columbia University" [March, Francis A.]
    - "Memories of My Last Days at Columbia"
    - "On Recent Results of Psycho-Physical Researches"
    - "Organization of Scientific Men"
    - "Perceptions, Images and Movements
    - "Philosophy and Scientific Methods"
    - "Possible Decline and Fall of the Human Race"
    - "President Butler's Athletic Record"
    - "Psychological Corp."
    - "Psychology"
    - "Psychology and Materialism"
    - "Red Flag"
    - "Scientific Career in the United States"
    - "Size of Families of College Graduates"
    - "Statistical Study of Eminent Men"
    - "Taxation for Education"
    - "Time It Takes to Think"
    - "Training of the Memory"
    - "University Professor"
    - "Vital Statistics and the Marriage Rate"
    - "Way We Read"
    - "Welfare of the People"
    - "What the Trustees of Columbia University Have Done"
    - Undergraduate papers prepared at Lafayette College, 1878-1880
    - Book review
    - Letters to the editor
    - Fragments
    - Publications of Cattell
  - Books (Box 187)
    - Carnegie Pensions (reviews)
    - University Control
    - Fragments
- Part II: Miscellany, 1839-1940 (Box 188-190)
  Miscellaneous material.
  Organized by type of material and arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Articles by others (Box 188)
  - Bills and receipts
  - Biographical material
  - Biographical material (Box 189)
  - Business papers
  - Family papers
  - Genealogical papers
  - Laboratory journals
  - T.T.S. (secret society)
  - General membership lists, articles by others (Box 190)
  - Printed matter